Thank you, my boy.
Good job.
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you,
sir.
A very important guest is arriving today
from Boston. Mr. Samuel Bodden. The
Samuel Bodden?
The big retailer who... Who closed
nearly half the North American
Yes, that Samuel bought it. And I want
you in particular to take especially
care of him.
You can count on me, sir.
I've had a smoother ride in an ox cart.
May I help you, sir? Don't touch that.
I'll carry it.
Yes, sir. What about the rest of your
luggage? Take my bags to my room at
Sort of a primitive place have I come
to.
Well, what are you standing around for?
Help me in.
Yes, Mr. Bodden.
Hear you back, sir. Staple's out.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Keep your hands off that.
Yes, sir.
I'm Felix King. If there's anything I
can do for you, anything at all, just
Pot of tea.
Strong. Yes, sir. I'll have it sent up
right away. In the dining room.
Book me a table. Yes, sir. I'll see what
I can do.
By the window.
Yes, sir.
I'm sorry, sir. We're all full up.
That's the summertime crowd.
I can teach in...
45 minutes.
45 minutes? Young man, that's absurd.
I'm sorry, ma 'am. We're fully booked.
Can you book room 12 with table for tea?
45 minutes.
45 minutes?
Surely there's something that can't be
done. I'm a paying guest at this hotel.
I'm sorry, ma 'am. We're doing our very
best. If you'd like to leave your room
number... Gus, I've got to have a table
by the window now.
Felix, I couldn't fit a sardine in
there. It's so packed.
Room 12 is Mr. Barton. He's rich.
He's got this release that he won't let
anyone touch. I bet it's full of money.
Think of the debt.
Well, I can't boot people out of their
tables.
What am I supposed to tell Mr. Barton?
Well, I'll do my best to have a table
for you in half an hour.
By the window.
Don't push your luck.
30 minutes?
Preposterous. I can bring some tea up to
your room if you like.
So this is the legendary White Sands
Hospitality I've heard so much about,
which I'm paying a small fortune. Tea in
an airless cubicle.
Actually, sir, it's more... I own and
supervise more than 100 businesses, boy,
and not one of them is as poorly run as
this.
Well, are there any other eating
establishments in the area?
Well, sir, there's Peter's Tea Room up
the coast, but, uh...
I wouldn't go there if I were you.
Around here we call it Poison Pete's.
Well, you can hardly send people to the
competition now, can you?
Oh, just what I need.
A draft.
Is there anything else I can do for you,
sir?
Yes.
You can get out.
You'll be careful. Yes, do be careful.
There's delicate china in there.
It's come all the way from storage in
Montreal without mishap. To be broken
would be tragic.
Oh, feels like a ton of bricks in here.
What was that, Alec? I said, where would
you like it, dear? Well, somewhere
where I shan't be underfoot.
The kitchen, perhaps?
Oh, well, I'll be starting dinner, Aunt
Eliza. Well, that's all right, dear. You
won't be in my way.
Oh, the kids.
Yeah, didn't do too bad myself.
Could have made double if I had not
turned so many people away.
Yeah, the whole world wanted tea today.
Mr. Tremaine should expand his dining
room. There ain't no room to expand.
Too bad for all those rich people.
All that money.
Oh, my gosh, it's fixed already?
I've got a million chores to do when I
get home.
See ya.
Does everything have to come out of this
trunk?
Well, how do you expect me to sort it if
I don't take everything out?
Oh, of course.
Oh, oh, oh, Cecily, don't let Daniel
near that trunk.
Oh, look, dear, why don't you go out
early and gather the eggs? That's a
Come on, Daniel.
Would you mind very much, Janet, if I
left my samovar to Abigail?
After all, you will have my Limoges
dinner set when I go.
Well, Aunt Eliza, you do whatever you
think is fair. I have to set the table.
Oh, don't mix Abigail's things with
yours, Janet.
I don't know how you can decipher that
document, Eliza. It's been scribbled on
the chain so many times.
It's a terrible thing to leave this
earth, but it's far worse to leave it
your affairs in a muddle.
I'd like to wager your own will isn't in
order.
Oh!
I've been after Alec to change that will
ever since Daniel was born.
Well, there's nothing to change. I'm
leaving everything to you, Janet.
What if Janet goes first?
Eliza, please.
Sorry I'm late. It was really busy at
the hotel.
Yes, and you haven't finished cleaning
out the stalls.
I'll do it as soon as I change.
What if you go together?
You could both be hit by a train.
Somehow, I don't think that's too
likely.
Oh, it can happen.
My cousin Freddy was hit by a train.
Or was it Reginald?
Who was hit by a train?
Was someone hit by a train? No one,
dear. No one was hit by a train.
And what about the farm?
Oh, do we really have to discuss this?
All this talk about death is so morbid.
It's not morbid.
It's realistic.
The only certain thing about life is
that we must leave it. Well, the only
certain thing to me is that I have to
have dinner on the table.
Look at all the tips I made.
Well, that's all well and good, Felix,
but you do have chores to do.
I'll finish the stall store.
What about the farm?
Who will have the farm?
Well, that's obvious.
Felix is the eldest son. The eldest son
always gets the farm. As I did, my
father before me, and the line will
continue with Felix.
Now, that's a frightening thought.
Oh, Felicity, I made him feel bad.
You'd actually trust the farm to Felix?
He'll eat more than he can produce.
Felicity.
The chance of a lifetime.
Just think.
Tired of waiting for tea at the White
Sands?
No problem. No need to wait.
Come to Felix's Tea Room.
Best view on the island.
Everyone will come.
I could rake in enough money to get my
own carriage and driver.
No more biking to work.
Who knows?
I might even make enough money to buy an
automobile.
Bring the motor car around, James.
No, not the black one today.
The new red one.
So how's it going?
Almost finished.
What about the cows?
I'll bring them in when I'm done here.
That's my son.
You know what happened at work today?
Mr. Tremaine told me I had a real feel
for the hospitality business.
He even gave me sort of a promotion.
He put me in charge of someone real
important.
Really?
Oh, that's good.
Felix, you know, your sister's remark
about your taking over the farm being a
frightening thought, that was...
I'm called for it. No one really feels
that.
Unless you feel that.
No. Where'd you get an idea like that?
I love the farm.
It's just that I don't really feel I'm
capable of running it.
Good, good.
For a moment there, I thought you
weren't interested.
Yeah, it's... It's quite a challenge,
farming.
Deciding how many acres to...
Put into corn, and how many to wheat,
how many pigs to keep for the winter,
what to do when the frost comes early or
the winter stays too long.
It's always a struggle with nature.
A beautiful struggle. You've got to stay
on your toes, be resourceful. That's
what makes it so rewarding.
I see what you mean.
Come over here.
I want to show you something.
You see that binder?
I'm saving up to buy one.
You better keep up with the times. I
mean, that is the future of agriculture
right there.
Mechanization. Your future.
My future?
Felix, don't be overwhelmed at the
thought of taking over. You just need a
little more experience.
When you get working with that land, you
become part of it. It gets in your
blood.
Tomorrow?
I am going to give you more
responsibility.
I'm going to put you in charge of fixing
the fences now. You know, that's
important work. You've got to do it
right. Do you feel up to it?
Sure.
Right, then.
And you'll remember our deal.
George, before the hotel, I know.
Good.
Now, that fence out in the eastern
pasture needs fixing, will you?
Give it a look.
You can count on me.
That's my boy.
More tours.
Great.
Of course I know it will take a lot of
money, but look at this place. It's full
of money. I can smell the tips from
here.
I'm saving up.
You're dreaming.
I wonder how much a person like Mr.
Bodden is worth.
Forget Bodden. He's a real tightwad. He
never tips.
Last night at dinner, I waited on him
hind and foot.
Nothing.
Bet you I could get a tip out of him.
Bet you can't.
How much?
One day's worth of tips.
It's a deal.
Easiest tip money I ever made.
Well, you haven't seen the King Charming
action.
Can I take those for you?
About time somebody cleared the dishes.
I've had better service than the
Australian outback.
Are you planning on seeing anything
while you're on the island?
I know this place like the back of my
hand.
The cliffs over by the lighthouse are
particularly dramatic.
Or maybe fishing is your game. If so, I
could take you to many lovely and
private spots where the fish are
practically asking to be caught.
Or maybe you just want to sit back,
relax, and enjoy a good book. But I'd be
more than happy to go over to Carmody
and get you... I don't care about cliffs
or fishing holes or novels. I care about
my breakfast.
Porridge tasted like dishwater, the egg
was like a rock, and very soon this
coffee will be cold. But if you don't
let me finish it in peace, I shall
complain to the management.
Please, go away.
That King Charm bowls them over every
time, Felix.
have one tray this size.
Would you like it, Janet?
Oh, yes. It's lovely, isn't it,
Felicity?
Yes, it's beautiful.
This trunk has got to be moved. This is
a kitchen here, not your private
storeroom.
On second thought, I think Abigail could
use it more.
We have this.
That looks like it's made of hair from
the heads of the ward
ancestors.
Father used to call it the family
heirloom.
It's a joke, you see.
Heirloom.
Lovely, isn't it?
Well, yes.
Very interesting.
Look at all those different...
Coloured. Felicity, there's one very
similar to your shade.
A little bit more sheen to it, of
course, but... You shall have it, Janet.
I'll find a safe place to put it away
and keep it for you.
Thank you.
Mother, it's horrible.
There is no room in this house for that
piece of... Oh, now, just pretend you
like it.
I mean, by the time we get it, the old
dear will be... Well, you know, I
We'll never have to hang it.
What she doesn't know won't hurt her.
Mother, why can't you just tell Great
Aunt Eliza which things you want and
things you don't want?
Not the way these things are done,
Felicity.
Well, maybe it's the way they should be
done.
Helig?
Here I am.
Ready to work.
Well, I hope you're ready to do a better
job than you did this morning.
What do you mean? I found a whole bag of
chicken feed out.
I know I put it on the shelf. Well, I
found it on the floor. I suppose you
know that you milked all the cows?
Of course I did. Well, you didn't. You
missed one.
And that cow was in a lot of pain.
I'm sorry.
Running a farm takes your full
attention.
You've got to use your head.
Yes, sir. I know that. I'm not going to
be around forever. You've got to learn
to take over.
I know.
If your farm work suffers, you've got to
give up that hotel.
I can do both jobs.
Don't worry.
That's all very well and good. But I'd
like to know where my bags are, then.
They're not here.
Felix, didn't you get Mrs. Trilby's
bags?
Mrs. Trilby, roommate.
Yes, they're right here. They aren't
mine. Young man, I was in room 10.
Incompetence. Pure incompetence. I'm
sorry.
My luggage has been stolen. Stolen? It
was in my room when I came down for
lunch. Excuse me?
Roommate? Yes?
I'll take it right up.
where I will check to make sure that
nothing is missing. And don't forget my
luggage while you're up there. My train
departs in an hour. I can't afford to
miss it, or I won't make the ferry at
Summerside.
Oh, but it's pure incompetence.
He looks dear.
Wake up. Paul, don't. Be there in a
minute.
Not morning? No.
You go to bed now.
Go to bed.
Good night, Mother.
Good night.
Why didn't you wake me? I'm going to be
late.
I thought I'd let you sleep in. You
seemed so tired last night.
Oh, look, the cows.
That post on the east pasture still
needs fixing.
I'll do it.
The hat you were talking about?
Yes.
Try it on.
If you like it, you may have it.
I love it.
Belonged to my dear cousin Margaret.
A beautiful girl.
Though in the end, she went quite bald,
poor dear.
Some sort of scalp fungus, they said.
Whatever are they doing in the yard?
Good yard.
Come on, girl.
Come on.
Oh, my goodness.
Get that one. Get that one.
What do you want?
The church already, sir.
Ah, about time.
There's starch in them.
You asked for starch. I distinctly said
no starch.
I'm sorry, Mr. Barton, but I know you
said starch.
Oh, you do, do you? Do you think I like
my shirts stiff as boards?
Look here.
A broken button.
This is precisely why I didn't want
starch in my shirts, to avoid this rough
handling. It's ruined.
Completely ruined.
We'll replace the button.
You'll never match these buttons.
We'll replace all the buttons.
Oh, I'm sure you will. With cheap,
ordinary buttons.
You'll pay for this.
Is anything wrong, sir? Yes.
This hotel employs cretins.
A slower, more incompetent worker I have
never seen.
Get this babbling numbskull out of my
sight. I want to speak to the manager.
Get me the manager!
But it wasn't my fault. It wasn't. No,
he did ask for starch.
Some people are unreasonable.
Unfortunately, that's a fact of life.
Unreasonable? He's impossible.
Part of running a hotel is dealing with
the impossible.
Perhaps we should let someone else care
for Mr. Bodden.
No, it's all right. I'll do it.
I'm sorry, Felix, but I must insist that
someone else tend to him.
I'm highly disappointed, Felix.
I spent the whole day rounding up cows.
One of them got in the corn crib. She
could have bloated and died.
Did you nail in that fence support?
No. Why not?
I didn't think it was necessary.
Well, of course it was necessary. I
fixed it myself.
Now, when I ask you to do something, I
expect it to be done properly, not
slapdash. I can't do everything.
I'm not asking you to do everything.
You gave me too much.
You agreed to take on more
responsibility.
There's not enough time to do it all.
Well, if that's the case, you're going
to have to give up that job at the
Why?
This farm is where you are going to earn
your livelihood, not that hotel. Your
first responsibility is here.
I'm doing the best I can.
Well, you can do better.
It's that hotel.
I'm not going to give up the White
Sands.
You will if I tell you to. I hate this
stupid farm! Felix, I do not want to be
farmer. That was your idea, not mine.
I am not interested.
And if you are going to give this place
to me when you die, the first thing I am
going to do is steal it!
So if you don't want to be a farmer,
well, what do you want to do?
A tea room?
There are more and more tourists on the
island.
Rich people from Toronto, Maine, Boston,
New York.
They have to eat, right?
Well, they can go to the White Sand.
Not all of them.
Mr. Tremaine has to turn some guests
away. Oh, and you think they're going to
come to Felix's Tea Room?
They will if it's good.
It's going to be good.
Well, the tea room's just the beginning.
Later I'll expand and have a restaurant.
The best down the island.
I'll have to turn people away, just like
the white sand. I have never heard a
more ridiculous idea in all my life.
Not ridiculous?
Working at that hotel has filled your
head with nonsense. I don't understand
this obsession you have with money.
We make a good living from the farm. You
never want for anything.
It's not the money.
I love the hotel.
I love working there, and I'm good at
it.
Well, mostly.
I want to stay and run the business.
Someday I'll have a place to run of my
own.
You'll have a farm to run.
I don't want the farm.
I want something... something exciting.
You're too young to know what you want.
Enough of this nonsense. Let's go.
Are you coming?
I'll be along with you.
We won't be needing that much firewood
for several months.
Where have you been?
Letting off a little steam.
Where's Felix?
Probably doing the same.
You know what your stubborn fool of a
son wants to do?
Open up a tea room.
A tea room? I mean, it's for old
biddies. It's something I'd expect your
Eliza to dream up. Where does he come up
with these crazy notions?
Well, he's always had a mind of his own.
I can understand him wanting to leave
the farm to study, to be a veterinarian,
go to university, but something serious,
or at least practical, but a tea room,
Janet. You worry too much.
You know, Felix.
Changes mind seven days a week about
what he wants to do.
Well, this farm is what we kings stand
for. It's our history. You can't just
walk away from something like this.
You can't.
Apparently, Felix can.
Oh, that was his age.
There's nothing I like better than
swinging a scythe working alongside my
father. You know, I think if you push a
child too hard in one direction, he'll
just run as fast as he can in the other.
Alec, if I'd done everything my father
wanted me to do, I never would have
married you.
The hotel is a dream.
Boys have to dream.
Yes, well, fathers have dreams, too.
Boy, you can't get enough of this place.
It's not even your shift.
I'm not here to work. I need a place to
sleep.
What's wrong with your bed at home?
Hmm?
What happened?
Do you know how lucky you are?
You are so lucky.
I've been called lots of things.
Lucky ain't one of them.
You're lucky all right.
You're independent.
No one tells you what to do.
Well, many's a time I've wished I did
have someone to guide me.
You don't have your father that expects
you to do everything he's planned for
you.
Whatever the problem is, Felix, you
ought to talk it out with him.
There's no talking to my father.
Well, run away is not going to solve
anything.
Neither is going back.
Now, I'm willing to pay my hard -earned
tip money for a room.
Well, there aren't any. We're all full
up.
There's got to be someplace.
can't be choosers.
Felicity, would you stop by Olivia's
when you're out and see if she has a
of black thread?
Why can't Felix go?
Felix is not back yet.
Don't you think you should go look for
him?
Where do you suggest I start?
Oh, he'll be all right. You know.
I mean, well,
he knows how to look after himself.
I've never been one to interfere, Alec.
But why are you working that boy so
hard?
When I was his age, I was a fancy tree,
going to dance classes, rolling hoops,
feeding the pigeons in the park.
I'm just trying to say that you're only
young once.
And you're old for a long time.
Felix.
Why would he knock?
It's probably Gus.
Good evening to you, Mr. King.
Come inside, Gus.
Thank you.
Here's your coke.
Ready to go, Felicity?
I'm on.
You haven't seen Felix this evening,
have you?
Yes, I have.
He's down at the hotel.
What's he doing at the hotel?
Planning to spend the night, I reckon. I
fixed him up a cot.
I'll go get him.
I'd leave him be if you don't mind me
saying.
He's pretty teft.
You got yourself a real independent
thinker there, Mr. Kang.
Oh, he knows his own mind, all right.
Unfortunately, it's in the wrong
direction most of the time.
Oh, perhaps.
But I don't ever recollect seeing him
like this before.
Oh, well.
Oh, this trunk is everywhere I go.
You said you wanted to take it out of
the kitchen. I want it out of the house.
Now, don't get everyone to dither.
Well, tell Felix that. He's at the root
of the problem. He's off sulking
somewhere because we want to hand over
the best piece of property on the
We want to give him the farm.
It's not fair.
What isn't fair?
I can tell you.
We call this the king farm, which means
it ought to belong to all of us.
Now, I may never run this farm, and I'm
not saying that I want to, but I can't
for the life of me imagine why you'd
want to leave the workings of it to
who doesn't care a lick about it.
That's your father you're talking to.
Well, what are you trying to say?
Look how often you have to remind Felix
to do things around here.
But have you ever noticed that when you
ask Cecily to do a chore, you never have
to tell her twice?
It's because Cecily loves this farm.
She should be the one who inherits it.
That's not the way things are done,
Felicity.
Why do things always have to be done the
way they used to be?
Because there are certain traditions.
Well, why can't we start new traditions?
I'm ready, Gus. Let's go.
Mr. Barton?
Do you need help?
Go away.
Can't you see I've been ill?
Can I call a doctor?
Just leave me alone.
Here we go.
All ready?
Let me get these out of your way and...
No, no, even though you were sick.
Here, let me help you.
Thank you, young man.
I think I may just survive.
Food poisoning.
That's what it was.
Not the food at our hotel.
No, I had luncheon up the coast.
Poison feeds?
I got tired of all the lineups here.
I guess that'll teach me.
I'll put in a word for you with Mr.
Tremaine.
Thanks, but it doesn't matter.
I'm quitting the hotel.
My father's making me work at the farm.
Probably for the rest of my life.
You don't want to do that?
No.
Have you told him?
He doesn't listen.
So you and your father don't see eye to
eye, huh?
Hand me my valise.
This is my beloved wife and son.
I lost Vanessa 12 years ago.
12 years, 2 months, 7 days.
I'm sorry.
All I had left was my son.
My only son.
He was 6 months old when that picture
was taken.
Went on to graduate at the top of his
class at the university.
We had our differences.
I naturally assumed he'd join the family
business, carry on the Borden name.
He wanted to be a missionary in China.
I told him it was out of the question.
He left.
We never settled our quarrel.
Why don't you try to find him now?
Because he died in China three years ago
during a cholera epidemic.
I'm sorry.
I can't tell you what to do. What I can
tell you is...
All the money in the world won't make
you happy if there's a rift between
and son.
Now, you go back to bed.
I'll be all right.
I'll just stay here a while.
Make sure you're all right.
What is this?
Resignation.
Resignation?
Look, Felix, if this is about all that
foolishness with Mr. Bodden... It's not
just that.
I've spent the past week trying to
please everyone and ending up pleasing
one.
I wish I could stay, but I don't see how
I can.
I understand.
I hate to lose you.
I hate to go.
Goodbye.
Mother.
Felix, are you all right?
I'm fine.
I quit my job at the hotel.
I'll get to my chores.
Daniel and I are feeding the chickens
for you.
Thanks.
I want you to have this.
It's my final wages.
You can put it towards the binder.
I should be happy, shouldn't I?
Doing exactly what I wanted them to.
Why don't I feel better about it?
Remember to spread the feed around,
Daniel.
That's the way.
If you put it all in a pile, the
chickens will fight with each other.
Last night, I sat up thinking about this
farm and all my years on it.
Well, at least I tried to think about
that, but for some odd reason, all I
think about was the first time I left
the farm.
I was about your age, and they'd just
finished putting in the track for the
first train on the island.
I begged my father to take me, and he
did.
Did you like it?
I like it. I loved it.
It was the most exciting adventure of my
young life. But my father, he hated it.
Oh, he couldn't stand all the noise and
the swaying and how fast it went. The
very things that I loved about it.
I can still hear him.
Trapped him my whole life with a horse
and buggy. Got me where I wanted to go,
didn't I? What do we need with this
infernal contraption?
He, uh, he put a damper on my good time,
that's certain.
Things change, Felix.
Not always the way you want them to, but
I suppose it's my turn
to learn how to enjoy the ride.
Here, you take this money. It's yours.
No. Yes.
You worked mighty hard for it, and I'm
proud of you.
So here's what I want you to do.
You keep working hard, and you save your
money.
And when you're 18, you can buy anything
you want with it.
Trip around the world, or stable a race
horses, or maybe
a binder, or even property there.
Build a tea room on it, if that's what
you want.
Thank you.
And I'll, uh... I'll give you more time
off from your chores.
What?
Well, you want to do a good job at the
hotel, don't you?
If you think Mr. Tremaine will have you
back.
I haven't given up on him, you know.
Eighteen's a long way off.
Maybe he'll have had his fill of the
hotel business by then.
Or... Maybe we'll
start a new tradition.